地球
1988年
劲歌金曲  第一辑
彼得
Peter.
妈妈有话跟你说
Your momma wants to speak with you.
快点  彼得  把这傻玩意儿摘掉
Come on, Pete. Take these fool things off.
宝贝  你怎么又跟别的小孩打架了
Why have you been fighting with the other boys again, baby?
彼得
Peter?
他们弄死了一只无辜的小青蛙
They killed a little frog that ain't done nothing.
用棍子把它捅烂了
Smushed it with a stick.
你真像你爸爸
You're so like your daddy.
长得也很像
You even look like him.
他是个天使
And he was an angel.
-他就是光  -梅
- Composed out of pure light. - Mer?
你不是有礼物要给他吗
You got a present there for Peter, don't you?
当然
Of course.
给
There.
我帮你放好了  彼得
I've got you covered, Pete.
等我走了以后再打开好吗
You open it up when I'm gone, okay?
外公他会
Your grandpa...
好好照顾你的
is gonna take such good care of you.
至少在爸爸回来接你之前这段时间
At least until your daddy comes back to get you.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
彼得
Peter.
彼得  过去啊
Pete, come on.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
妈妈
Mom?
不  不  不  不
No! No! No! No!
妈妈  不要走
Mom! No!
-跟我来  -不
- Come with me. - No!
不
No!
待在这里别动  听话
You've got to stay here. Please.
不要
No...
好吗
Okay?
不
No.
妈妈
Mom!
26年之后
莫拉格
废弃星球
放下它
Drop it!
-立刻放下  -哥们儿  没问题
- Drop it, now! - Hey, cool, man. No problem.
一点问题都没有
No problem at all.
你怎么知道这东西的
How do you know about this?
我连它是什么都不知道
I don't even know what that is.
我就是个捡破烂的  就随便翻翻
I'm just a junker, man. I was just checking stuff out.
你可不像捡破烂的
You don't look like a junker.
你穿着掠夺者的制服
You're wearing Ravager garb.
就是件外套而已
This is just an outfit, man.
忍者神龟  你别戳我了
Ninja Turtle, you better stop poking me.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
我叫彼得·奎尔  兄弟  冷静点
My name is Peter Quill, okay? Dude, chill out.
-跟我走  -为什么
- Move! - Why?
罗南可能有话要问你
Ronan may have questions for you.
你知道不
Hey, you know what?
你可能听过我另外一个名字
There's another name you might know me by.
星爵
Star-Lord.
谁
Who?
星爵啊  传奇侠盗
Star-Lord, man. Legendary outlaw.
-各位  -快走
- Guys? - Move!
算了
Forget this.
彼得
Peter?
出什么事了
What happened?
-布瑞特  -对了布瑞特
- Bereet. - Bereet!
说实话吧  我都忘了你还在这儿
Look, I'm gonna be totally honest with you. I forgot you're here.
克里帝国今天发生了
Scattered riots broke out
多起小规模暴乱
across the Kree Empire today
抗议最近克里大帝
protesting the recent peace treaty
与山达尔的新星至尊签订的和平条约
signed by the Kree Emperor and Xandar's Nova Prime.
彼得  有电话找你
Peter, you have call.
-不  等等  别  -奎尔
- No, wait, don't! - Quill?
你好啊  勇度
Hey, Yondu.
我人在莫拉格
I'm here on Morag.
没看到宇宙灵球也没看到你
Ain't no Orb, ain't no you.
我之前就在那附近
Well, I was in the neighborhood.
我可帮你解决了个大麻烦
I thought I'd save you the hassle.
那你小子现在在哪
Well, where are you at now, boy?
很抱歉  可我不打算告诉你
I feel really bad about this, but I'm not gonna tell you that.
-我千辛万苦给你牵了线  -千辛万苦
- I slaved putting this deal together. - Slaved?
打几个电话就千辛万苦了  不是吧
Making a few calls is "slaved"? I mean, really?
你这是要坑我
And now you're gonna rip me off!
我们掠夺者不这么做事  我们有原则
We do not do that to each other. We're Ravagers. We got a code.
原则就是 "能抢就抢"
Yeah, and that code is "steal from everybody."
我从地星把你捡来的时候
When I picked you up on Terra...
"捡来"
"Picked me up."
我手下这些人可是想吃掉你的
these boys of mine wanted to eat you.
是吗
Yeah?
他们以前没吃过地星人肉
They ain't never tasted any Terran before.
我制止了他们  你活下来多亏了我
I stopped them. You're alive because of me!
我会找到你的  我要
I will find you, I will...
悬赏捉拿他
Put a bounty on him!
四万
Forty K.
-但我要捉活的  -是  船长
- But I want him back alive. - Yeah, Cap.
-捉活的  -你没听错
- Alive? - That's what I said.
你捡走他的时候我就跟你说了
I told you when you picked that kid up,
就该按照客户要求把他送过去
you should have delivered him like we was hired to do!
他不过是我们的货
He was cargo!
你对他一直太心软了
You have always been soft on him.
我看是对你太心软了
You're the only one I'm being soft on!
你别给我操心奎尔先生的事了
Now, don't you worry about Mr. Quill.
一旦把他抓回来
As soon as we get him back here,
我会亲手了结他
I'm gonna kill him myself.
我们需要操心的是
What we do need to worry about,
还有谁想得到那个灵球
is who else out there wants that Orb!
暗黑星号
克里战舰
他们称我为"恐怖分子"
They call me "Terrorist, "
"激进派"  "狂徒"
"Radical", "Zealot",
就因为我谨遵我克里子民的世代法则
because I obey the ancient laws of my people, the Kree,
严惩违背法则者
and punish those who do not.
因为我拒绝原谅你们的同族
Because I do not forgive your people
杀死我父亲
for taking the life of my father,
父亲的父亲和祖父的行为
and his father, and his father before him.
我们两族间持续千年的战争永不会被遗忘
A thousand years of war between us will not be forgotten!
你不能这样  双方政府签署了和平条约
You can't do this! Our government signed a peace treaty.
我们的政府没有羞耻心
My government knows no shame.
山达尔人还有山达尔文明都是祸害
You Xandarians and your culture are a disease.
你
You
永不可能统治山达尔
will never rule Xandar.
不
No.
我是要治愈它
I will cure it!
罗南
Ronan,
克拉斯回来了
Korath has returned.
主人  那人就是个贼
Master, he is a thief,
一个自称星爵的法外之徒
an outlaw who calls himself Star-Lord.
但我们发现他跟一个叫
But we have discovered he has an agreement
"掮客"的中间人定下协议
to retrieve the Orb for an intermediary
拿回宇宙灵球
known as The Broker.
我跟灭霸保证过帮他拿回宇宙灵球
I promised Thanos I would retrieve the Orb for him.
那样他才帮我毁灭山达尔
Only then will he destroy Xandar for me.
星云  去山达尔帮我拿到宇宙灵球
Nebula, go to Xandar and get me the Orb.
这将是我的荣幸
It will be my honor.
这将是你的末路
It will be your doom.
要是你再次失败
If this happens again,
父亲可不会给你奖励
you'll be facing our father without his prize.
我是灭霸的女儿
I'm a daughter of Thanos.
和你一样
Just like you.
但我对山达尔更熟
But I know Xandar.
罗南已经命令我来...
Ronan has already decreed that I...
不要替我做决定
Do not speak for me.
你不可以失败
You will not fail.
我失败过吗
Have I ever?
山达尔
新星帝国首都
山达尔人
Xandarians.
都是一群废柴
What a bunch of losers.
所有人不是忙着做无聊事
All of them in a big hurry to get from something stupid,
就是做无用功  真令人同情
to nothing at all. Pathetic.
看这个人
Look at this guy!
还管我们叫罪犯
Can you believe they call us criminals,
拿那个发型吓人才是犯罪
when he's assaulting us with that haircut?
这是什么东西  还自以为多炫酷
What is this thing? Look how it thinks it's so cool.
让人帮算什么酷
It's not cool to get help!
有本事自己走啊  小怪兽
Walk by yourself, you little gargoyle.
你看那边的"微笑先生"
Look at Mr. Smiles over here.
你老婆在哪呢  老头子
Where's your wife, old man?
极品老变态
What a class-A prevert.
是吧  格鲁特
Right, Groot?
格鲁特
Groot?
别喝喷泉里的水  你个白痴
Don't drink fountain water, you idiot.
太恶心了
That's disgusting!
你喝了  我刚看到了
Yes, you did. I just saw you doing it.
为啥要说谎
Why are you lying?
看来我们有目标了
Looks like we got one.
愚蠢的人类  看看你值多少钱
Okay, humie, how bad does someone wanna find you?
四万  格鲁特  我们要变有钱人了
40,000 units? Groot, we're gonna be rich.
-奎尔先生  -掮客
- Mr. Quill. - Broker.
宇宙灵球
The Orb.
-任务完成  -勇度呢
- As commissioned. - Where's Yondu?
他本来想亲自来的  但只能送上问候
Wanted to be here. Sends his love.
同时让我转告
And told me to tell you,
你的眉毛是同行里最酷炫的
that you got the best eyebrows in the business.
这是什么意思
What is it?
我不可以透露客户和他们的要求
It's my policy never to discuss my clients, or their needs.
为了拿到它我可是九死一生
Yeah, well, I almost died getting it for you.
干你们这行就是有这样的风险
An occupational hazard, I'm sure, in your line of work.
一个机械脑袋怪物
Some machine-headed freak,
自称是什么罗南的手下
working for a dude named Ronan.
罗南  抱歉了  奎尔先生
Ronan? I'm sorry, Mr. Quill.
真的很抱歉
I truly am.
但凡是跟罗南扯上关系的交易
But I want no part of this transaction
我是不会介入的
if Ronan is involved.
罗南是什么人
Who's Ronan?
一个克里的狂徒  被和平条约所激怒
A Kree fanatic, outraged by the peace treaty,
除非山达尔文明  我的文明被彻底清除
who will not rest until Xandarian culture, my culture,
否则他不会罢休的
is wiped from existence!
-拜托  -他这种人
- Come on. - He's someone
我招惹不起
whose bad side I'd rather not be on.
不是吧  那我就可以招惹吗
What? What about my bad side?
再会无期  奎尔先生
Farewell, Mr. Quill.
我们有约定在先的  老兄
Hey, we had a deal, Bro!
怎么了
What happened?
这家伙翻脸不认账
This guy just backed out of a deal on me.
我最讨厌的就是不守信用的男人
If there's one thing I hate, it's a man without integrity.
彼得·奎尔  大家都叫我星爵
Peter Quill. People call me Star-Lord.
看得出你是个正人君子
You have the bearing of a man of honor.
我也没那么好啦
Well, you know, I wouldn't say that.
大家倒都这么说我
People say it about me, all the time,
不过我一般不会这么夸自己
but it's not something I would ever say about myself.
这就不能怪我了
This wasn't the plan.
把他装进袋子  把他装进袋子
Put him in the bag. Put him in the bag!
不  不是她  是他
No! Not her, him!
要分清性别啊
Learn genders, man.
不带咬人的
Biting? That's not fair!
放松
Take it easy!
蠢货  你该长点记性
Fool. You should have learned.
我从不长记性  缺点之一
I don't learn. One of my issues.
搞什...
What the...
别笑了  白痴  表现得专业点
Quit smiling, you idiot. You're supposed to be a professional.
饶了我吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我满足起来很容易
I live for the simple things.
比如想想这样会有多疼
Like how much this is gonna hurt.
没错  颤抖吧  凡人
Yeah. Writhe, little man.
还会再长出来的  你个二缺
It'll grow back, you d'ast idiot.
别嘤嘤了
Quit whining.
实验体89P13  放下武器
Subject 89P13, drop your weapon.
该死
Aw, crap.
以新星军团的名义
By the authority of the Nova Corps,
-你们被逮捕了  -好了  站起来
- you are under arrest... - All right. Come on up.
罪名是危害他人生命及破坏财产
for endangerment to life and the destruction of property.
这不是星王子吗
Hey! If it isn't Star-Prince.
-星爵  -抱歉了爵爷
- Star-Lord. - Sorry. "Lord."
我之前因为小偷小摸抓过他
I picked this guy up a while back for petty theft.
他还有个代号呢
He's got a code name.
请让开
Yeah. Stay out of the way.
拜托  一听就是个大盗的名字啊
Come on, man. It's a... It's an outlaw name.
没事的  小哥
Just relax, pal.
有代号挺酷的  也没有很奇怪了
It's cool to have a code name. It's not that weird.
法西斯
Fascists.
新星总部-山达尔武装部队
罗南正在全星系
Ronan is destroying
新星总部-山达尔武装部队
摧毁山达尔人在各处建立的前哨站
Xandarian outposts throughout the galaxy.
我认为这应该值得
I should think that would call
克里方面稍稍作出一些回应吧
for some slight response on the part of the Kree.
我们已经签订和平条约了  新星至尊
We signed your peace treaty, Nova Prime.
你还想要什么
What more do you want?
至少克里帝国方面
At least a statement from the Kree Empire
应该谴责他的行为
saying that they condemn his actions.
他正在屠杀儿童
He is slaughtering children.
破坏家庭
Families.
这就是你们的事了
That is your business.
我现在还有其他事要忙
Now, I have other matters to attend to.
混蛋
Prick.
好消息
Well, some good news.
我们好像逮捕了罗南的同伙
It looks like we've apprehended one of Ronan's compatriots.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
经受过全身改造  训练成了杀人机器
Surgically modified and trained as a living weapon.
"疯狂泰坦"灭霸的养女
The adopted daughter of the Mad Titan, Thanos.
最近灭霸派她和星云姐妹两人去辅佐罗南
Recently, Thanos lent her and her sister Nebula out to Ronan,
因此我们有理由相信
which leads us to believe
灭霸和罗南有勾结
that Thanos and Ronan are working together.
实验体89P13  自称"火箭"
Subject 89P13. Calls itself "Rocket."
在低等生命体上
The result of illegal genetic
进行非法基因改造和机械实验的产物
and cybernetic experiments on a lower life form.
什么鬼东西
What the hell?
他们叫它"格鲁特"
They call it "Groot."
近来作为89P13的私人植物及打手
A humanoid plant that's been travelling recently
陪伴其行动的类人植物
as 89P13's personal houseplant/muscle.
彼得·杰森·奎尔  来自地星
Peter Jason Quill, from Terra.
自幼被勇度·尤冬塔领导的佣兵组织"掠夺者"
Raised from youth by a band of mercenaries called the Ravagers,
抚养成人
led by Yondu Udonta.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道这机器是怎么运作的
I didn't know how this machine worked.
真是一帮子混球
What a bunch of a-holes.
把四个都送到克林去
Transport all four to the Kyln.
克林
高安保级别监狱
我猜新星军团成员一般都遵纪守法
I guess most of Nova Corps wanna uphold the laws,
可这里这些人腐败又残忍
but these ones here, they're corrupt and cruel.
反正我是不用担心
But, hey, that's not my problem.
我待不了多久的
I ain't gonna be here long.
我越过22次狱  这个也不例外
I've escaped 22 prisons. This one's no different.
这个妞出现是算你走运
You're lucky the broad showed up,
不然我和格鲁特
because otherwise, me and Groot
现在已经拿到赏金了
would be collecting that bounty right now,
至于你  已经被勇度和那些掠夺者
and you'd be getting drawn and quartered
五马分尸了
by Yondu and those Ravagers.
这些年想杀我的人可太多了
I've had a lot of folks try to kill me over the years.
怎么可能被一棵树和一只会说话的浣熊拿下
I ain't about to be brought down by a tree and a talking raccoon.
等等
Hold.
-浣熊是什么鬼  -浣熊是什么鬼
- What's a raccoon? - "What's a raccoon?"
你自己就是啊  傻货
It's what you are, stupid.
老子是这世上独一无二的
Ain't no thing like me, except me.
这个宇宙灵球是《死吻》中的神秘箱子
So, this Orb has a real shiny blue suitcase,
《夺宝奇兵》里的约柜
Ark of the Covenant,
还是《马耳他雄鹰》里的雕像啊
Maltese Falcon sort of vibe.
-到底是什么  -我是格鲁特
- What is it? - I am Groot.
所以呢  那个宇宙灵球是什么
So what? What's the Orb?
我对阴险的小偷没什么好说的
I have no words for an honorless thief.
你还是个想灭绝别人的疯子的走狗呢
Pretty high and mighty coming from the lackey
真理直气壮
of a genocidal maniac.
对  我知道你是谁
Yeah, I know who you are.
大家都知道你是谁
Anyone who's anyone knows who you are.
对  我们知道你是谁
Yeah, we know who you are.
-她是谁  -我是格鲁特
- Who is she? - I am Groot.
你已经说过了
Yeah, you said that.
我不是来帮罗南拿回宇宙灵球的
I wasn't retrieving the Orb for Ronan.
我背叛了他
I was betraying him.
我已经私下跟第三方买家谈好了
I had an agreement to sell it to a third party.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
你这句话说得
Well, that's just as fascinating
跟之前89次一样令人耳目一新
as the first 89 times you told me that.
这爱心树什么毛病
What is wrong with Giving Tree, here?
他没法像你我这样正常说话
Well, he don't know talking good like me and you.
所以他的词库里只有"我"
So his vocabulistics is limited to "I"
"是"和"格鲁特"三个词
and "am" and "Groot."
顺序乱了都不行
Exclusively in that order.
你知道吗  我的忍耐就要到极限了
I tell you what, that's gonna wear real thin, real fast.
给我放下
Put that away.
你个蓝皮怪  把那耳机摘下来
Listen to me, you big blue bastard. Take those headphones off.
那是我的  应该被扣押起来的
That's mine. Those belong to impound.
那磁带还有播放器  都是我的
That tape and that player is mine!
那是1973年蓝色瑞典人的
Hooked on a Feeling,
《迷上一种感觉》
Blue Swede, 1973.
那是属于我的歌
That song belongs to me!
-你死定了  你死定了  -凶手
- You first! You first! - Murderer!
老子先宰了你  卡魔拉  你死定了
Coming for you first, Gamora! You're dead!
你个垃圾  贱货
You're scum! You're scum!
我说过吧
It's like I said,
她名头响着呢
she's got a rep.
这里有好多囚犯的亲人
A lot of prisoners here have lost their families
都死在了罗南和他的狗腿子手下
to Ronan and his goons.
她最多撑一天
She'll last a day, tops.
杀人犯
Murderer!
警卫会保护她的吧
The guards will protect her, right?
他们只管阻止我们逃出去
They're here to stop us from getting out.
在里面怎么作死他们才不管
They don't care what we do to each other inside.
无论未来有什么大风大浪
Whatever nightmares the future holds,
跟我的经历比起来  也都是
are dreams compared to what's behind me.
瞧瞧这个新来的鲜肉
Check out the new meat.
我要把你浑身抹满古纳维恩液
I'm gonna slather you up in Gunavian jelly,
然后好好爽一发
and go to town...
先把话说清楚
Let's make something clear.
这小子的菊花是我们的
This one here is our booty!
你们想动他
You wanna get to him,
先过我们这一关
you go through us!
或者  说得更准确些
Or, more accurately,
我们先做了你
we go through you.
我是他们的
I'm with them.
我恨你们
I hate you.
再结实的牢房也别想保你的命
No cell's gonna protect you for long.
你死定了
You're dead!
死定了
Dead!
把她带到浴室去
Take her down to the showers.
那里血迹容易清理
It'll be easier to clean up the blood down there.
奎尔  你干什么去
Quill, where you going?
奎尔
Quill.
Quill!
卡魔拉  我现在宣判你的死刑
Gamora, consider this a death sentence
为你对全银河系犯下的罪行偿命吧
for your crimes against the galaxy.
你敢
You dare?
你知道我是谁吧
You know who I am, yes?
你是德拉克斯
You're Drax.
毁灭者
The Destroyer.
奎尔
Quill!
你知道我这名号怎么来的吧
And you know why they call me this.
你宰过罗南手下数十个恶棍
You slayed dozens of Ronan's minions.
罗南杀了我妻子  奥薇特
Ronan murdered my wife, Ovette,
还有我女儿  卡玛莉亚
and my daughter, Camaria.
他将她们残杀致死
He slaughtered them where they stood.
但他却笑了
And he laughed!
奎尔
Quill?
她的命
Her life
轮不着你们来取
is not yours to take.
他杀了我家人
He killed my family.
我也要杀了他的家人
I shall kill one of his in return.
当然好  德拉克斯  给你  我
Of course, Drax. Here, I...
奎尔  你干什么
Quill! What are you doing?
我绝不是罗南或灭霸的家人
I'm no family to Ronan or Thanos.
我是你阻止他的唯一希望
I'm your only hope at stopping him.
女人  你的话对我一文不值
Woman, your words mean nothing to me!
-别  别别别别  -见鬼
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hey! - Crap.
如果你的目标是杀了罗南
You know, if killing Ronan is truly your sole purpose,
杀了她也没法帮你实现目标
I don't think this is the best way to go about it.
这贱女人不是也刺杀过你吗
Are you not the man this wench attempted to kill?
反正她也不是第一个
Well, I mean, she's hardly the first woman
想杀我的女人了
to try and do that to me.
你看  这疤是一个巨火辣的拉贾克妞弄的
Look, this is from a smoking-hot Rajak girl.
拿叉子戳出来的
Stabbed me with a fork.
她不乐意我大清早就离她而去
Didn't like me skipping out on her at sunrise.
这条疤是因为有个克里妞想把我的胸腔破开
I got, right here, a Kree girl tried to rip out my thorax.
我在和新星档案处
She caught me with this
一个瘦瘦的阿斯卡瓦里安妞
skinny little A'askavariian
鬼混时被她抓包了
who worked in Nova Records.
我只是想套些消息而已
I was trying to get information.
你见过阿斯卡瓦里安人吧
You ever see an A'askavariian?
她们长着触角  牙齿跟针一样
They have tentacles, and needles for teeth.
你觉得我真会看上...
If you think I'm seriously interested in that, then...
好吧你不在乎  但我想说的是
You don't care. But here's the point.
她背叛了罗南  他会来追杀她
She betrayed Ronan. He's coming back for her.
等他自己找过来
And when he does,
到时你就可以
that's when you...
我为什么要把手指放在他的喉咙上
Why would I put my finger on his throat?
啥
What?
这只是个手势
No, it's a symbol.
这个手势表示你割了他的喉咙
This is a symbol for you slicing his throat.
我才不想割他的喉咙
I would not slice his throat.
我会一刀砍了他的脑袋
I would cut his head clean off.
这是通用手势啊  意思是杀人
It's a general expression for you killing somebody.
你听说过  见过这手势  对吧
You've heard of this. You've seen this, right?
-你知道这什么意思吧  -知道  知道
- You know what that is. - Yeah. Yeah.
-人人都知道  -不知道  不知道
- Everyone knows. - No, no.
我就是想说  你最好留她一命
What I'm saying is, you want to keep her alive.
别帮你敌人的忙
Don't do his work for him.
我喜欢你的刀  我收下了
I like your knife. I'm keeping it.
-那是人家最喜欢的刀  -听着
- That was my favorite knife. - Listen!
我才懒得管你是死是活
I could care less whether you live or whether you die.
-那你拦下那大个子干什么  -简单
- Then why stop the big guy? - Simple.
你知道能把宇宙灵球卖给谁
You know where to sell my Orb.
我们和那东西都困在这里  你怎么卖
How are we gonna sell it when we and it are still here?
我这位火箭老兄
My friend Rocket, here,
成功越狱22次
has escaped 22 prisons.
我们肯定出得去
We're getting out.
然后我们直奔勇度那里去取你的赏金
And then we're headed straight to Yondu to retrieve your bounty.
你那买家打算花多少钱买我的宇宙灵球
How much was your buyer willing to pay you for my Orb?
四十亿
Four billion units.
-多少  -我操
- What? - Holy shit.
宇宙灵球是我逃离灭霸和罗南的机会
That Orb is my opportunity to get away from Thanos and Ronan.
如果你能越狱
If you free us,
我就直接带你去见买家
I'll lead you to the buyer directly
卖的钱我们三个平分
and I'll split the profit between the three of us.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
四人平分
Four of us.
出事儿了睡大觉  一听见钱就来精神
Asleep for the danger, awake for the money,
死性不改
as per frickin' usual.
你被背叛了  罗南
You have been betrayed, Ronan.
我们只知道她被捉住了
We know only that she has been captured.
卡魔拉也许还有机会取回宇宙灵球
Gamora may yet recover the Orb.
错  我们在克林的线人
No! Our sources within the Kyln
说卡魔拉对宇宙灵球自有打算
say Gamora has her own plans for the Orb.
你跟灭霸的合作
Your partnership with Thanos
已经岌岌可危了
is at risk.
灭霸要见你  现在就见
Thanos requires your presence. Now!
圣域-灭霸领地
.
恕我直言  灭霸
With all due respect, Thanos,
圣域-灭霸领地
是你女儿惹下的麻烦
your daughter made this mess,
圣域-灭霸领地
你却传唤我过来
and yet you summon me.
你最好说话小声些  指控者
I would lower my voice, Accuser.
她先是败在一群原始人手下
First, she lost a battle with some primitive.
灭霸把卡魔拉交由你调遣
Thanos put Gamora under your charge.
然后还被新星军团送进大牢
Then she was apprehended by the Nova Corps.
现在空口无凭的人是你
You are the one here with nothing to show for it.
是你的线人说她早已谋划背叛我们
Your sources say that she meant to betray us the whole time!
放尊重点
Lower your tone!
我虽是你的
I may be your...
我只希望您把这当回事
I only ask that you take this matter seriously.
小子  我不当回事的
The only matter I do not take seriously, boy,
只有你了
is you.
你的政治权术真无聊
Your politics bore me.
你做事像个闹脾气的孩子
Your demeanor is that of a pouty child.
而且很显然
And, apparently,
是你逼走了我最爱的女儿  卡魔拉
you alienated my favorite daughter, Gamora.
我会践行我们的约定的  克里人
I shall honor our agreement, Kree,
但你务必将宇宙灵球带给我
if you bring me the Orb.
如果下次见我时你再两手空空
But return to me again empty-handed,
我就用你的血染红整个星系
and I will bathe the starways in your blood.
多谢了  父亲  很公平
Thanks, Dad. Sounds fair.
这场争斗你赢不了
This is one fight you won't win.
我们去克林吧
Let's head to the Kyln.
如果我们想逃出去
If we're gonna get out of here,
得设法进到那边的瞭望塔里
we're gonna need to get into that watchtower.
为此我需要几件东西
And to do that, I'm gonna need a few things.
警卫都佩戴着安保臂带
The guards wear security bands
来控制人员进出  我要一个
to control their ins and outs. I need one.
交给我
Leave it to me.
那边那位  我需要他的假腿
That dude, there. I need his prosthetic leg.
-他的腿  -对
- His leg? - Yeah.
其他的部分我可不需要
God knows I don't need the rest of him.
瞧瞧他  废物
Look at him, he's useless.
好吧
All right.
最后一样  后边的墙上
And finally, on the wall back there
有块黑色面板  闪着黄灯的
is a black panel. Blinky yellow light.
-瞧见了没  -看见了
- Do you see it? - Yeah.
里面有块柯尼斯电池
There's a quarnyx battery behind it.
紫颜色的  接着绿色电线
Purplish box, green wires.
要想进瞭望塔  我需要这东西
To get into that watchtower, I definitely need it.
要怎么才能拿到
How are we supposed to do that?
这群秃头佬应该觉得你挺美
Well, supposably, these bald-bodies find you attractive.
所以你可以色诱一个
So, maybe you can work out some sort of trade.
你逗乐呢吧
You must be joking.
没有  我真听他们说你挺美
No, I really heard they find you attractive.
你看  那东西离地20英尺
Look, it's 20 feet up in the air,
而且还处在
and it's in the middle of
一座戒备森严的监狱正中央
the most heavily-guarded part of the prison.
想要不被发现  绝不可能
It's impossible to get up there without being seen.
我想了个计划
I got one plan,
而这计划他妈的还就需要柯尼斯电池
and that plan requires a frickin' quarnyx battery,
所以你给我想办法去
so figure it out!
我接着说了哈  多谢
Can I get back to it? Thanks.
接下来这点非常重要
Now, this is important.
一旦电池被取下来
Once the battery is removed,
监狱就会进入警戒状态
everything is gonna slam into emergency mode.
所以一旦得手  就必须迅速行动
Once we have it, we gotta move quickly,
因此务必在最后一步再取下电池
so you definitely need to get that last.
或者先拿电池  再随机应变
Or we could just get it first and improvise.
-我去取臂带  -我去拿腿
- I'll get the armband. - Leg.
囚犯
Prisoner,
立即放下该设备  退回监房
drop the device immediately and retreat to your cell,
否则我们就开火了
or we will open fire.
我  是
I am
格鲁特
Groot!
开火
Fire!
所有囚犯立即返回休息区
All prisoners return to your sleeping areas.
你个白痴
You idiot!
家伙不在手上  我怎么跟这些东西打
How am I supposed to fight these things without my stuff?
是那动物在指挥
The animal is in control.
听我命令准备开火
Fire on my command!
猥琐的小怪物
Creepy little beast!
这才像话
Yeah.
你想要我的啥
You need my what?
-把这个给我  -请便吧
- I'll need this. - Good luck.
这是内置在体内的
It's internally wired.
我自有办法
I'll figure something out.
把腿放下
Drop the leg!
把腿放下  回到自己监房去
Drop the leg and move back to your cell!
火箭
Rocket!
朝瞭望塔前进
Move to the watchtower!
你
You!
睡过阿斯卡瓦里安人的男人
Man who has lain with an A'askavariian!
就那么一次而已
It was one time, man.
所有待命警卫请全副武装
We need all available guards in full combat gear...
不要怨恨地盯着我  女人
Spare me your foul gaze, woman.
这家伙来干什么
Why is this one here?
我们答应了
We promised him he could
让他跟着我们  直到手刃了你老大
stay by your side until he kills your boss.
我向来信守承诺
I always keep my promises,
尤其是面对一个肌肉呆男
when they're to muscle-bound whack-jobs
我不同意就宰了我的时候  给你
who will kill me if I don't. Here you go.
腿我是开玩笑的
I was just kidding about the leg.
我只需要这两样东西
I just need these two things.
-什么  -我就觉着会挺好笑啊
- What? - No, I thought it'd be funny.
多好笑啊
Was it funny?
等等  他单腿跳是个什么样子
Wait, what did he look like hopping around?
我可是花了三万块买的他的腿
I had to transfer him 30,000 units!
我们要怎么逃脱
How are we going to leave?
他想好计划了
Well, he's got a plan.
有的吧  难道也是编出来逗人玩的
Right? Or is that another thing you made up?
有计划的  我有计划的
I have a plan! I have a plan!
别再唧唧歪歪的了
Cease your yammering
赶紧带我们冲出这恼人的监牢吧
and relieve us from this irksome confinement.
这回我跟这个活字典
Yeah, I'll have to agree with the walking thesaurus
看法相同
on that one.
不准再叫我字典
Do not ever call me a thesaurus.
就是个比喻而已  哥们
It's just a metaphor, dude.
他们只能理解字面意思
His people are completely literal.
弄个比喻就绕晕了
Metaphors are gonna go over his head.
我怎么绕都不晕的
Nothing goes over my head.
我的反应特别快  肯定能走出去
My reflexes are too fast. I would catch it.
我要全银河最蠢的人死在一起了
I'm gonna die surrounded by the biggest idiots in the galaxy.
那些枪威力可不小
Those are some big guns.
听我号令
On my command!
第一发
Number one!
耗子  你的计划呢
Rodent, we are ready for your plan.
急什么
Hold on!
第二发
Number two!
我认得这种动物
I recognize this animal.
我们小时候会拿来架在火上烤
We'd roast them over a flame pit as children.
肉质相当鲜美
Their flesh was quite delicious.
帮倒忙呢你
Not helping!
第三发
Number three!
全体听我号令
All fire on my command!
三
Three!
二
Two!
一
One!
他把人工重力关掉了
He turned off the artificial gravity,
除了这座瞭望塔里的
everywhere but in here.
我就说我有计划
I told you I had a plan.
这计划真是太完美了
That was a pretty good plan.
太好了  在那边  去开我的飞船
Yeah! There it is. Get my ship.
米拉诺号  那边角落里橙蓝相间的那艘
It's the Milano, the orange and blue one over in the corner.
居然把我的裤子卷成一团
They crumpled my pants up into a ball.
真没礼貌  你们的都是叠好了的
That's rude! They folded yours.
宇宙灵球在里面呢  快走
The Orb's there. Let's go.
-等下  等下等下  -怎么了
- Wait, wait, wait. - What?
那混蛋没放回来
That bastard didn't put it back.
-什么没放回来  -拿着
- Put what back? - Here.
带到船上去  我随后就到
Get them to the ship. I will be right back.
你打算怎么
How are you gonna possibly...
让米拉诺号停在附近就行
Just keep the Milano close by.
走吧
Go.
快走啊
Go!
我的脖子
My neck!
他打算怎么跟我们会合
Well, how's he gonna get to us?
他拒绝向我透露相关信息
He declined to share that information with me.
那就去他的
Well, screw this, then!
我才不想傻等一个作死的人类
I ain't waiting around for some humie with a death wish.
宇宙灵球在你手上呢  是吧
You got the Orb, right?
对
Yes.
如果现在再不走  我们会被轰成渣的
If we don't leave now, we will be blown to bits.
不行
No!
宇宙灵球没到手决不能走
We're not leaving without the Orb.
快看
Behold.
你果然有胆识
This one shows spirit.
在和罗南对战时肯定是个得力帮手
He shall make a keen ally in the battle against Ronan.
朋友  你回去拿什么了
Companion, what were you retrieving?
真是个蠢材
You're an imbecile.
*浣熊形象的卡通人物
游侠瑞克  你这是在干嘛
Yo, Ranger Rick! What are you doing?
你怎么没经过同意就拆我的飞船
You can't take apart my ship without asking me!
-这是什么  -别碰那个
- See, what is this? - Don't touch that!
是个炸弹
It's a bomb.
-炸弹?  -对
- A bomb? - Yup.
你就把炸弹那样放着
And you leave it lying around?
我本来打算找个盒子放进去的
I was gonna put it in a box.
放到盒子里有用吗
What's a box gonna do?
-这个怎么样  -不行
- How about this one? - No! Hey!
-别碰  -为什么  这是什么
- Leave it alone. - Why? What is it?
闭嘴
Shut up.
那个是什么
What is that?
这是在万分危急时候用的
That's for if things get really hardcore.
或者想炸卫星时候用的
Or if you wanna blow up moons.
我不会让你们炸卫星
No one's blowing up moons.
乐趣都被你抹杀光了
You just wanna suck the joy out of everything.
我需要你联系的买家坐标
So, listen, I'm gonna need your buyer's coordinates.
暂时来说  我们的航行方向没有问题
We're heading in the right direction. For now.
如果你真想合作的话
If we're gonna work together,
至少试着多信任我点
you might try trusting me a little bit.
那你有多信任我
And how much do you trust me?
如果你告诉我这是什么
I'd trust you a lot more
我就能更信任你
if you told me what this was.
我猜这是某种武器
Because I'm guessing it's some kind of weapon.
我也不知道这是什么
I don't know what it is.
如果真是武器  那就能用来对付罗南了
If it's a weapon, we should use it against Ronan.
快放下  你个傻子  你会害死我们的
Put it down, you fool. You'll destroy us all.
只想害死你  女杀手
Or just you, murderess!
我可救了你一次  小娘子
I let you live once, princess!
我才不是娘子
I am not a princess!
在我的飞船上别闹出人命
Nobody is killing anybody on my ship!
我们得团结一致拿到钱
We're stuck together until we get the money.
我可不是为了钱
I have no interest in money.
棒极了
Great.
那我们三个又能多分点了
That means more money for the three of us.
我们四个
For the four of us.
伙伴们
Partners.
我们是有约在先
We have an agreement,
但我绝不会做你这种人的伙伴
but I would never be partners with the likes of you.
我去通知买家我们在路上了
I'll tell the buyer we're on our way.
奎尔  你的船真恶心
And Quill, your ship is filthy.
这才哪到哪
She has no idea.
用黑光灯一照
If I had a black light,
*美国抽象表现主义画家  以"滴洒"作画闻名
整艘飞船里都是我的涂鸦
the place would look like a Jackson Pollock painting.
你该吃药了  奎尔
You got issues, Quill.
我发誓  我真的不知道他们去哪了
I swear. I don't know where they went! I swear.
如果他知道的话
If he knew where they were headed,
早就告诉我们了
he would have already told us.
罗南
Ronan,
新星军团派了一支舰队过来守卫监狱
the Nova Corps sent a fleet to defend the prison.
那好吧
Well, then,
派死灵舰去找遍宇宙的每个角落
send Necrocraft to every corner of the quadrant.
给我找到灵球
Find the Orb.
不惜一切代价
Any means, any price.
这里怎么处置
And this place?
不能让新星知道我们在找什么
The Nova can't know what we're after.
全部解决了
Cleanse it!
你这儿还有这种可爱的小玩意吗
Do you got any other cute little buggers like this one?
我要在我的控制台旁摆一排
I like to stick 'em all in a row on my control console.
我分辨不出您是开玩笑还是认真的
I can't tell if you're joking or not.
他非常认真的
He's being fully serious.
那么我可以给您看看
In that case, I can show you...
但是你得先告诉我宇宙灵球到底是干嘛的
But first, you gonna tell me what this Orb is,
为什么每个人都他妈为之疯狂
and why everybody cares so damn much about it.
然后你还得告诉我
And then you gonna tell me,
真正的买家是谁
who out there might wanna buy it.
先生  高端客户群是...
Sir, the high-end community is a...
高端客户群是...
The high-end community is a...
是一个严格
It's a tight-knit...
严格的
Tight-knit...
高端客户群是一个严格的...
The high-end community is a very tight-knit...
我不可能出卖
I cannot possibly betray
买家的机密信息
the confidentiality of my buyers!
你再说说看谁是你的买家
Now, who again is this buyer of yours?
卡瑞娜
Carina.
请吩咐  主人
Yes, Master.
你们种族的人是有胳膊有肘的吧
Your people do have elbows, do they not?
是的  主人
We do, Master.
那就好好利用起来
Then use them.
我用不着提醒你
I don't have to remind you
上一个让我失望的侍从有什么下场了吧
what happened to the last attendant who disappointed me.
对吗
Do I?
快点快点  我们的客人马上就要到了
Chop, chop. Our guests will be here soon.
当心  我们要着陆了
Heads up! We're inbound.
这是哪
What is it?
他们称之为无存知地
It's called Knowhere.
原本是个远古天神的头颅
The severed head of an ancient celestial being.
小心驶入  耗子
Be wary headed in, rodent.
这里毫无秩序可言
There are no regulations whatsoever here.
无存知地
矿场
数百年前  蒂万集团派遣工人
Hundreds of years ago, the Tivan Group sent workers in
来开采这个头骨中的有机物
to mine the organic matter within the skull.
骨头  脑组织  还有脊髓液
Bone, brain tissue, spinal fluid.
都是稀缺资源
All rare resources,
不管在哪的黑市都能买上好价钱
highly valued in black markets across the galaxy.
这工作既危险又违法
It's dangerous and illegal work,
只适合亡命徒
suitable only for outlaws.
我本人就来自一个无法无天的星球
Well, I come from a planet of outlaws.
*均为美国家喻户晓的传奇罪犯
比利小子  邦尼和克莱德
Billy the Kid, Bonnie and Clyde,
*80年代著名演员  彼得被劫走同年他主演的《欢乐满屋》正在播放
约翰·斯塔莫斯
John Stamos.
听起来真不错  我倒想去瞧瞧
It sounds like a place, which I would like to visit.
是挺值得去
Yeah, you should.
打扰下
Excuse me.
-看紧钱包  -能给点钱吗
- Watch your wallets. - Can you spare any units?
快走开
Get out of here.
你的买家就在这里面
Your buyer's in there?
我们在这儿等他的代表
We are to wait here for his representative.
滚出去
Get out of here!
这可不是个体面的地方
This is no respectable establishment.
我们等待期间还能做点什么
What do you expect us to do while we wait?
好样的  好样的
Yes! Yes!
我的奥罗尼赢了
My Orloni has won,
我样样都是第一
as I won at all things!
再多灌点这液体吧
Now, let's put more of this liquid into our bodies.
你只有这句感觉没有那么疯
That's the first thing you said that wasn't bat-shit crazy!
天哪  他们这的燃料贵死了
Man, you wouldn't believe what they charge for fuel out here.
搞不好到最后我还得赔钱
I might actually lose money on this job.
我的联系人让我们先等着
My connection is making us wait.
只是种谈判策略  相信我  这我在行
It's just a negotiation tactic. Trust me, this is my specialty.
而你的风格是那种
Where yours is more,
左一刀  右一刀  这就是我的条件
"Stab, stab. Those are my terms."
我父亲没教过我怎么给人施压
My father didn't stress diplomacy.
灭霸吗
Thanos?
他不是我父亲
He's not my father.
灭霸入侵了我的母星
When Thanos took my home world,
在我面前杀了我父母
he killed my parents in front of me.
他折磨我
He tortured me,
把我改造成杀人机器
turned me into a weapon.
当他说要帮罗南摧毁整个星球时
When he said he was going to destroy an entire planet for Ronan,
我不能袖手旁观  所以
I couldn't stand by and...
为什么要冒着生命危险去取它
Why would you risk your life for this?
我母亲给我的
My mother gave it to me.
我妈妈喜欢和我分享
My mom liked sharing with
她年轻时喜欢的流行歌曲
me all the pop songs that she loved growing up.
碰巧我那天带在身上
I happened to have it on me,
那天我...
when I was...
那天她...
The day that she...
就是我离开地球那天
You know, when I left Earth.
你都用它做什么
What do you do with it?
做什么  什么都不做  只要去听
Do? Nothing. You listen to it.
你也可以跟着跳
Or you can dance.
我是名战士也是个杀手  我从不跳舞
I'm a warrior and an assassin. I do not dance.
真的吗
Really?
在我母星  有个关于你这样的人的传说
On my planet, there's a legend about people like you.
叫做
It's called
凯文·贝肯的歌舞电影  讲述的是舞者用舞技打破小城禁忌的故事
《浑身是劲》
Footloose.
故事讲的是一个叫
And in it, a great hero
凯文·贝肯的大英雄
named Kevin Bacon,
教会那个城市里
teaches an entire city full of people
所有的假正经[菊花塞着棍子]跳舞
with sticks up their butts that dancing, well...
是件很伟大的事
It's the greatest thing there is.
谁把棍子插进他们菊花里
Who put the sticks up their butts?
什么  不  这只是个...
What? No, that's just a...
-太残忍了  -这只是个俗语
- That is cruel. - It's just a phrase
大家都知道
people use.
旋律挺美的
The melody is pleasant!
-不  -搞什么
- No! - What the hell?
我知道你是什么样的人  彼得·奎尔
I know who you are, Peter Quill!
我是不会中了你的
And I am not some starry-eyed waif here to succumb to your...
你下贱的巫术的
Your pelvic sorcery!
不是你想的那样
That is not what is happening here.
不是吧
No.
快停下
Stop it!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
这爬虫什么都不懂  还说三道四的
This vermin speaks of affairs he knows nothing about!
-我说的都是事实  -他根本不尊重我
- That is true! - He has no respect!
-这也是事实  -慢着  慢着
- That is also true! - Hold on! Hold on!
你再叫我爬虫试试  傻大个
Keep calling me vermin, tough guy!
你和别人一样都只会嘲笑我
You just wanna laugh at me like everyone else!
火箭  你喝醉了  没人嘲笑你
Rocket, you're drunk. All right? No one's laughing at you.
他觉得我是什么可笑的东西  他说的
He thinks I'm some stupid thing! He does!
我也不想被改造啊
Well, I didn't ask to get made!
我也不想被大卸八块
I didn't ask to be torn apart,
然后被拆了又装
and put back together, over and over
最后变成什么
and turned into some...
什么小怪物
Some little monster!
火箭  没人叫你怪物
Rocket, no one's calling you a monster.
他叫我爬虫
He called me "Vermin"!
她叫我耗子
She called me "Rodent"!
让我们瞧瞧
Let's see if you can laugh
给你脸上来个四五发  你还笑不笑得出
after five or six good shots to your frickin' face!
别  别  别  别
No, no, no, no!
四十亿啊  火箭
Four billion units! Rocket!
想想吧  冷静点
Come on, man. Hey!
忍一忍  再受一晚上的罪
Suck it up for one more lousy night
你就有钱了
and you're rich.
好吧
Fine.
我可不保证这事完了后
But I can't promise, when all this is over
我不会把你们这群混蛋全杀了
I'm not gonna kill every last one of you jerks.
看到没  这就是为什么你们都没朋友
See? That's exactly why none of you have any friends!
跟别的人才认识五秒
Five seconds after you meet somebody,
你就想着要杀了他们了
you're already trying to kill them!
我们穿过了半个星系来到这
We have travelled, halfway across the quadrant.
连罗南的毫毛都没伤着
And Ronan is no closer to being dead.
-德拉克斯  -让他去
- Drax! - Let him go.
我们不需要他
We don't need him.
卡魔拉女士
Milady Gamora.
我过来接你去见我主人
I'm here to fetch you for my master.
这里一点也不诡异
Okay, this isn't creepy at all.
我们的馆藏珍品在整个星系是最多的
We house the galaxy's largest collection
动物  遗骸  不同物种应有尽有
of fauna, relics, and species of all manner.
容我为你们介绍
I present to you,
坦利亚·蒂万  收藏者
Taneleer Tivan, The Collector.
亲爱的卡魔拉
My dear Gamora.
能见到本尊真是荣幸
How wonderful to meet in the flesh.
省掉这些繁文缛节吧  蒂万
Let's bypass the formalities, Tivan.
我们有你要的东西
We have what we discussed.
那边那个是什么东西
What is that thing there?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我从来没想到能遇见个格鲁特
I never thought I'd meet a Groot.
先生
Sir...
请务必把您的尸体卖给我
You must allow me to pay you now
我现在就付款
so that I may own your carcass.
当然了  要等您死后
At the moment of your death, of course.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
怎么  给你拿去做个椅子吗
Why, so he could turn you into a frickin' chair?
这是你的宠物吗
That's your pet?
-他的什么  -蒂万
- His what? - Tivan.
我们穿越大半个银河系  取来了灵球
We have been halfway around the galaxy, retrieving this Orb.
非常好  那么
Very well, then.
让我看看你们带来的东西
Let us see what you brought.
三块柯尼斯电池  七箱科他蒂种子
Three quarnyx batteries, seven cases of Cotati seeds.
不  要七箱  上次你寄过来的
No, cases. Last time, you sent me...
你得帮我传达个信息
You shall send a message for me.
我的新朋友们
My new friends.
在宇宙开创之前
Before creation itself,
一共有六个奇点
there were six singularities.
然后宇宙大爆炸创造了万物
Then the universe exploded into existence,
这六个奇点的残留物
and the remnants of these systems
被收集起来凝炼成宝石
were forged into concentrated ingots.
称作无限宝石
Infinity Stones.
这些宝石似乎
These stones, it seems,
只有拥有非凡的力量
can only be brandished
才能驾驭
by beings of extraordinary strength.
请看
Observe.
这些携带者借助宝石能摧毁整个文明
These carriers can use the Stone to mow down entire civilizations
跟收麦子一样易如反掌
like wheat in a field.
我已经快吓尿了
There's a little pee coming out of me right now.
曾经有那么一次
Once, for a moment,
一个组织成功地共同控制了这股能量
a group was able to share the energy amongst themselves,
但即使是他们也很快被这力量摧毁了
but even they were quickly destroyed by it.
太美了
Beautiful.
无与伦比
Beyond compare.
我们都沉醉其中了  白毛
We're all very fascinated, whitey.
但是快给钱
But we'd like to get paid.
你们希望用什么方式付款
How would you like to get paid?
你说呢  花花公子  当然是现金
What do you think, fancy man? Units!
很好
Very well, then.
卡瑞娜
Carina.
别靠近
Stand back.
我再也不要做你的奴隶了
I will no longer be your slave!
不
No!
我了个
What the...
我怎么会相信蒂万
How could I think Tivan
知道如何控制宇宙灵球里的东西
could contain whatever was within the Orb?
你还拿着是要做什么
What do you still have it for?
不然怎么办  留在那儿吗
What are we gonna do, leave it in there?
你竟然还装进自己的荷包里了
I can't believe you had that in your purse!
这是个背包  不是荷包
It's not a purse, it's a knapsack!
我们必须把这个交给新星军团
We have to bring this to the Nova Corps.
他们可能知道如何控制它
There's a chance they can contain it.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
我们正在被新星军团通缉
We're wanted by the Nova Corps.
把它交给罗南就是了
Just give it to Ronan!
然后帮他毁了整个银河系吗
So he can destroy the galaxy?
怎么了你  突然变成圣人了吗
What are you, some saint all of a sudden?
银河系帮过你吗
What has the galaxy ever done for you?
你为什么想救它
Why would you wanna save it?
因为我就生活在这里面啊
Because I'm one of the idiots who lives in it!
彼得  听我说
Peter, listen to me.
绝不能让宝石落入罗南之手
We cannot allow the Stone to fall into Ronan's hands.
我们现在就回你飞船
We have to go back to your ship,
然后送去新星
and deliver it to Nova.
好的  就这样  你说得对
Right, right, okay. I think you're right.
或者我们可以把它交给某个
Or we could give it to somebody
不会逮捕我们的
who's not going to arrest us,
大好人
who's really nice
然后大赚一笔
for a whole lot of money.
我觉得这是个
I think it's a really good
能两全其美的好方法
balance between both of your points of view.
你太卑鄙
You're despicable.
太无耻
Dishonorable.
毫无信用
Faithless!
-不  -终于
- No. - At last!
我要面对我的仇敌并且亲手解决他了
I shall meet my foe and destroy him.
是你叫来了罗南
You called Ronan?
奎尔  别想跑  小子
Quill! Don't you move, boy!
你敢跑  别挡道
Don't you move! Get out of the way!
指控者罗南
Ronan the Accuser!
是你传送的信息吗
You are the one who transmitted the message?
你杀了我妻子
You killed my wife.
你杀了我女儿
You killed my daughter!
我都说了  你进不来的
I told you, you can't fit.
在这儿等我回来
Now, wait here. I'll be back.
是卡魔拉  她带着宇宙灵球逃走了
It is Gamora. She is escaping with the Orb.
不
No!
星云
Nebula,
去夺回宇宙灵球
retrieve the Orb.
宝石在最前面那个作业舱里
The Stone is in the furthest pod.
击落它
Bring it down!
火箭  掩护卡魔拉到米拉诺号
Rocket, keep them off Gamora until she gets to the Milano.
怎么掩护  这上面又没有武器
How? We've got no weaponry on these things.
这些作业舱都是工业级的
These pods are industrial grade.
基本上坚不可摧
They're nearly indestructible.
那也吃不消死灵炮啊
Not against necroblasts, they're not.
我可不是那个意思
That's not what I'm saying.
借你飞船用一用
Let me borrow your ride.
我不记得杀过你家人
I don't recall killing your family.
大概也不会记得杀过你
I doubt I'll remember killing you, either.
奎尔  我被困住了  到不了米拉诺号
Quill, I'm trapped. I can't make it to the Milano.
只能冲去外层空间了
I have to head out.
等等  这些作业舱不能飞到外层空间去
Wait! These things aren't meant to go out there.
你太让我失望了  姐姐
You are a disappointment, sister.
在所有姐妹当中
Of all our siblings,
我最不讨厌的就是你
I hated you least.
星云  别这样
Nebula, please.
如果罗南得到了宝石
If Ronan gets this stone
-他会杀光我们所有人  -不是所有人
- He'll kill us all. - Not all.
你活不到那时候
You will already be dead.
罗南  东西到手了
Ronan, it is done.
奎尔  算了
Quill, come on.
她的身体改造过  大概能撑几分钟
Her body mods should keep her alive a couple more minutes,
可我们没办法救她
but there's nothing we can do for her.
这些作业舱在外面坚持不了多久的
These pods aren't meant to be out here.
很快  我们也会像她一样
In a second, we're gonna be in the same boat.
去他的
Aw, damn it.
奎尔
Quill?
勇度  勇度
Yondu! Yondu.
我是奎尔
This is Quill!
-我现在的坐标是227K324  -奎尔
- My coordinates are 227K324. - Quill.
奎尔  你在干什么
Quill, what are you doing?
就在无存知地外面
Just outside Knowhere.
如果你在的话  就来抓我吧
If you're there, come get me.
我随你处置
I'm all yours.
奎尔  别犯傻
Quill, don't be ridiculous.
回你的作业舱里去
Get back into your pod!
里面装不下两个人  你会死的
You can't fit two people in there. You're gonna die.
你马上就会死的
You'll die in seconds!
奎尔
Quill.
Quill?
怎么了
What happened?
我看见你漂浮在外面
I saw you out there.
我也不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what came over me.
我不能眼睁睁让你死
But I couldn't let you die.
我突然感受到了内心深处的一种
I found something inside of myself.
一种
Something
难以置信的英雄气概
incredibly heroic.
我不是在夸自己
I mean, not to brag,
可是  客观地说
but, objectively...
宇宙灵球呢
Where's the Orb?
他们把宇宙灵球抢走了
It's... Well, they got the Orb.
什么
What?
欢迎回家  彼得
Welcome home, Peter.
蠢货  全是无可救药的蠢货
Blasted idiot. They're all idiots!
奎尔竟然自投罗网了
Quill just got himself captured.
要不是你
None of this ever would have
一意孤行  非要去单挑罗南
happened if you didn't try to single-handedly
这一切都不会发生
take on a frickin' army!
你说得没错
You're right.
我是个傻瓜
I was a fool.
所有的愤怒
All the anger,
所有的怨气
all the rage,
都是为了掩饰我的伤痛
was just to cover my loss.
"我的老婆孩子都死了"
Boo-hoo-hoo. "My wife and child are dead."
我才不在乎这有多残忍
I don't care if it's mean!
谁家没死过人
Everybody's got dead people.
不代表你就有理由让大家
It's no excuse to get everybody else
陪你一起送死
dead along the way!
好了  格鲁特  罗南拿到了宝石
Come on, Groot. Ronan has the Stone.
我们现在唯一能做的
The only chance we got
就是赶紧飞往宇宙另一头去
is to get to the other side of the universe
越快越好
as fast as we can and maybe,
也许趁着那神经病还没打过来
just maybe, we'll be able to live full lives
能安稳的过一辈子
before that whack-job ever gets there.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
救他们  怎么救
Save them? How?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我知道他们是我们唯一的朋友
I know they're the only friends that we ever had,
可他们现在落在掠夺者军队手里
but there's an army of Ravagers around them.
我们只有两个人
And there's only two of us!
是三个
Three.
我都被你们气得
You're making me
只能  拿草
beat...up
撒气了
grass!
宇宙灵球已经在我手里了
The Orb is in my possession,
我说到做到
as I promised.
把它送到我这里来
Bring it to me.
没错  这是我们之前约定好的
Yes, that was our agreement.
我帮你拿来宇宙灵球
Bring you the Orb,
你帮我毁灭山达尔
and you will destroy Xandar for me.
不过  既然我知道了它装有无限宝石
However, now that I know it contains an Infinity Stone,
我很好奇我还要你做什么
I wonder what use I have for you.
小子
Boy,
你最好给我想清楚了
I would reconsider your current course.
主人  你不能这么做
Master! You cannot!
灭霸是这宇宙中最强大的存在
Thanos is the most powerful being in the universe.
不再是了
Not anymore.
你竟然叫我"小子"
You call me "Boy!"
我会代表克里
I will unfurl
对千年来山达尔的所作所为进行审判
1,000 years of Kree justice on Xandar,
让它消失殆尽
and burn it to its core!
之后  灭霸
Then, Thanos,
我就去找你算账
I am coming for you.
毁灭山达尔之后  你会杀掉我父亲吗
After Xandar, you are going to kill my father?
你想反抗我吗
You dare to oppose me?
你也看到他对我做了些什么
You see what he has turned me into.
你杀了他  我会再帮你毁灭一千个星球
If you kill him, I will help you destroy a thousand planets.
你敢背叛我?
You betray me?
偷我的钱?
Steal my money?
住手  放开他
Stop it! Leave him alone!
你小时候刚被我捡到的时候
When I picked you up as a kid,
这些小子想吃了你
these boys wanted to eat you.
他们还没尝过地星人的味道呢
They ain't never tasted Terran before.
是我救了你
I saved your life!
还有完没完啊  天哪
Will you shut up about that? God!
二十年了  一直给我说这些陈芝麻烂谷子
Twenty years, you been throwing that in my face,
好像没有吃掉我是件多么伟大的事
like it's some great thing, not eating me.
正常人哪会每天想着吃人啊
Normal people don't even think about eating someone else!
不吃我难道我还得谢你吗
Much less that person having to be grateful for it!
是你劫持了我
You abducted me, man.
把我从家里掳走  害我无亲无故
You stole me from my home and from my family.
你他妈才不是因为在乎你们地星
You don't give a damn about your Terra!
你害怕
You're scared
不过是因为内心太懦弱了
because you're soft in here.
这里  就在这里
Here, right here!
勇度
Yondu!
听我说
Listen to me.
罗南掌握着一块叫无限宝石的东西
Ronan has something called an Infinity Stone.
我知道他手里有什么  小姑娘
I know what he's got, girl.
那你就该知道  我们必须把它抢回来
Then you know we must get it back!
他会用宝石摧毁掉山达尔
He's gonna use it to wipe out Xandar.
我们得警告他们
We have to warn them.
否则无数的人会因此丧命
Billions of people will perish.
她就是这样给你洗脑的吗  小子
Is that what she's been filling your head with, boy?
多愁善感
Sentiment?
蛆虫一样蚕食掉你的大脑
Eating away your brain like maggots!
就这样吧
That's it.
不
No!
抱歉了  小子
Sorry, boy.
身为队长  必须杀一儆百
But a captain's gotta teach his men
让手下知道背叛会是什么下场
what happens to those what cross him.
队长要以身作则
Captain's gotta teach stuff!
如果你现在杀了我
If you kill me now,
就别想做成这辈子最大一笔生意了
you are saying goodbye to the biggest score you have ever seen.
无限宝石吗
The Stone?
你最好能想出个别的
I hope you got something better than that.
没有人能从罗南手里偷东西
Because ain't nobody stealing from Ronan.
我们有秘密武器
We got a ringer.
是吗
Is that right?
她清楚有关罗南的一切
She knows everything there is to know about Ronan.
他的舰队
His ships,
他的部下
his army.
他也有弱点
He's vulnerable.
你觉得怎么样  勇度
Hey, what do you say, Yondu?
我和你  还跟以前一样  携手作战
Me and you, taking down a mark side-by-side, like the old days.
放开他
Let him go!
你小子一向有种
You always did have a scrote, boy!
所以我当时才留你在身边
That's why I kept you on as a young'un.
队长  这种攻击不痛不痒的
Captain, the shot was non-damaging.
请注意  蠢货们
Attention, idiots.
飞船上这个疯子手里拿着的是强子枪
The lunatic on top of this craft is holding a Hadron Enforcer.
我独家设计的武器
It's a weapon of my own design.
这是在搞什么
What the hell?
要是你们不赶紧交出我朋友
If you don't hand over our companions now,
他就把你们的飞船轰出个新鲜的洞
he's gonna tear your ship a new one.
又大又新鲜的洞
A very big new one!
-老子才不买你的账  -我倒数五下
- I ain't buyin' it. - I'm giving you to the count of five.
-5  4  3  -别  等一下
- 5, 4, 3... - No! Wait, hold on!
火箭  是我  真是的
Rocket, it's me, for God sakes!
已经谈拢了  我们没事了
We figured it out! We're fine!
奎尔  怎么回事
Hey, Quill. What's going on?
这就叫"谈拢了"
You call that "Figured it out"?
要从那群把我们
We're gonna rob the guys
打得屁滚尿流的家伙手里抢东西
who just beat us senseless.
你还有脸说屁滚尿流
You want to talk about senseless?
你到底是想救我们还是想把我们炸飞
How about trying to save us by blowing us up?
他们要是不交出你们
We were only gonna blow you up
我才会把他们炸飞
if they didn't turn you over!
你只数五下
And how on earth were they gonna turn us over
他们哪有时间交出我们
when you only gave them a count of five?
我们又没空考虑倒数时间
We didn't have time to work out the minutiae
那些细节
of the plan.
我们为朋友两肋插刀就这下场
This is what we get for acting altruistically.
-我是格鲁特  -他们根本不领情
- I am Groot. - They are ungrateful.
重点是
What's important now
我们说服了掠夺者军队
is we get the Ravagers' army
帮我们拯救山达尔
to help us save Xandar.
然后我们再把宝石交给勇度
So we can give the Stone to Yondu
好让他卖给一个更邪恶的家伙吗
who's just gonna sell to somebody even worse?
这个之后再议
We'll figure that part out later.
我们必须阻止罗南
We have to stop Ronan.
怎么阻止
How?
我有个计划
I have a plan.
你有个计划?
You've got a plan?
没错
Yes.
首先  那句话是我说的
First of all, you're copying me from
-你算是抄袭  -哪有
- when I said I had a plan. - No, I'm not.
这话谁都会说
People say that all the time.
又没什么特别的
It's not that unique of a thing to say.
其次  我不相信你有什么计划
Secondly, I don't even believe you have a plan.
我有一部分计划
I have part of a plan!
一部分是多少
What percentage of a plan do you have?
鉴于你在无存知地的表现
You don't get to ask questions
你没有权利提问
after the nonsense you pulled on Knowhere.
我可救了奎尔
I just saved Quill.
我们已经讨论过了
We've already established
你们想炸了我乘坐的飞船  那可不是在救我
that you destroying the ship that I'm on is not saving me.
我们什么时候讨论过了
When did we establish it?
就几秒钟以前
Like three seconds ago!
我没在仔细听  那会儿正走神
I wasn't listening. I was thinking of something else.
她说得没错  你没有发表意见的权利
She's right. You don't get an opinion.
你有百分之多少的计划
What percentage?
我不知道  百分之十二吧
I don't know. Twelve percent.
百分之十二?
Twelve percent?
你笑得真假
That's a fake laugh.
-是真的  -太假了
- It's real! - Totally fake.
这是我这辈子笑得最真实
That is the most real, authentic,
最歇斯底里的一次了
hysterical laugh of my entire life
因为你这是狗屁计划
because that is not a plan.
只能算是一个想法
It's barely a concept.
你站到他们那一边去了吗
You're taking their side?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
是比百分之十一要强点  又怎样
So what, it's better than 11%?
你那狗屁计划能有什么用
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
谢谢你  格鲁特  谢谢
Thank you, Groot. Thank you.
格鲁特是你们当中唯一一个明事理的
See? Groot's the only one of you who has a clue.
伙伴们
Guys.
拜托
Come on.
勇度马上就要过来了
Yondu is gonna be here in two seconds.
他还想听听我们的大计划呢
He expects to hear this big plan of ours.
我需要你们的帮助
I need your help.
看看我们
I look around at us.
知道我看到了什么吗
You know what I see?
一群失败者
Losers.
我们就像
I mean, like,
一群失魂落魄的家伙
folks who have lost stuff.
确实如此  我们所有人都失去过
And we have. Man, we have. All of us.
失去了家
Our homes,
失去了家人
our families,
失去了正常的生活
normal lives.
没错  生活本来就是付出比回报更多
And, usually, life takes more than it gives.
可今天不是
But not today.
今天我们得到了眷顾
Today, it's given us something.
生活给了我们一个机会
It has given us a chance.
什么机会
To do what?
去拼一回
To give a shit.
仅此一回
For once.
不要逃避
Not run away.
罗南要屠杀无数无辜的生命
I, for one, am not gonna stand by and watch
而我  绝不会袖手旁观
as Ronan wipes out billions of innocent lives.
可是  奎尔  想要阻止罗南
But, Quill, stopping Ronan,
是不可能的
it's impossible.
你是在叫我们去送死
You're asking us to die.
是啊  应该是吧
Yeah, I guess I am.
奎尔
Quill.
我活了这么久  只跟敌人打过交道
I have lived most my life surrounded by my enemies.
我愿意和朋友共生死
I will be grateful to die among my friends.
你是个有担当的男人  奎尔
You are an honorable man, Quill.
我愿意跟你并肩作战
I will fight beside you.
最后
And in the end,
我就能和我的妻女团聚了
I will see my wife and daughter again.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
随你们吧  反正本来我也活不长
What the hell. I don't got that long a lifespan, anyway.
我也站起来了  你们满意了吧
Now I'm standing. Y'all happy?
现在我们都站起来了
We're all standing up now.
一群傻缺  站成个圈圈
Bunch of jackasses, standing in a circle.
宝石会对任何有机体产生反应
The Stone reacts to anything organic.
目标越大  威力越强
The bigger the target, the bigger the power surge.
罗南只需要让宝石
All Ronan's got to do is
接触到星球的表面  它就会毁掉一切
touch the Stone to the planet's surface and zap.
所有的植物  动物
All plants, animals,
-新星军团  -一切都将被毁灭
- Nova Corps. - Everything will die.
所以不能让罗南登陆
So Ronan does not make the surface.
火箭带领一队人马在暗黑星号右舷
Rocket will lead a team to blow a hole
轰开一个洞
in the Dark Aster's starboard hull.
这样我们和勇度的飞船就可以攻进去了
Then, our craft and Yondu's will enter.
里面有上百个萨卡士兵把守吧
Won't there be hundreds of Sakaaran soldiers inside?
萨卡士兵都是纸做的
I think of Sakaaran as paper people.
他们一旦得知我们登陆了
Once they know we're on board,
罗南会关上舱内的安全门
Ronan will isolate himself
把自己隔离起来
behind impenetrable security doors on deck.
我可以通过破坏动力系统解锁
Which I can disable by dismantling the power source.
接着我们进到驾驶舱
We'll make it to the flight deck,
用强子枪把罗南轰上天
and I'll use the Hadron Enforcer to kill Ronan.
罗南一死我们就回收宝石
Once Ronan is dead, we will retrieve the Stone.
记得要把它装进这些装置里
Use these devices to contain it.
别直接触摸
If you touch it,
不然小命就没了
it will kill you.
我会联络之前逮捕过我们的新星警官
I'll contact one of the Nova officers who arrested us.
但愿他们相信我们是来帮忙的
Hopefully, they'll believe we're there to help.
正在呼入
但愿他们相信我们是来帮忙的
Hopefully, they'll believe we're there to help.
彼得·奎尔  正在呼入
完成计划还需要最后一步
There's one more thing we need to complete the plan.
那家伙的眼睛
That guy's eye.
不  瞎说什么呢
No! No, we don't.
我们不需要那家伙的眼睛
No, we don't need that guy's eye.
不  说真的  对我来说相当重要呢
No, seriously, I need it! It's important to me.
已发现罗南舰队
Ronan's fleet has been spotted,
预计十五分钟后抵达
and will arrive in T-minus fifteen minutes.
听好了  小子
Remember, boy.
这事完了之后
At the end of all this,
宝石归我
I get the Stone.
敢耍我就砍死你们
You cross me, we kill you all.
准备大干一场吧  小子们
Let's go get 'em, boys!
这计划烂死了
This is a terrible plan.
不是你说要和朋友共生死的吗
Hey, you're the one who said you wanted to die among friends.
新星至尊
Nova Prime.
一个掠夺者刚刚给我传达了一则消息
I received a transmission from one of the Ravagers.
他说罗南得到了一颗什么无限宝石
He says Ronan's in possession of something called an Infinity Stone
正冲着山达尔来
and he's headed toward Xandar.
老天爷
Good God.
不过是个幌子  别忘了他是罪犯
It's a trick. He's a criminal.
他有说我们为什么要相信他吗
Did he say why we should believe him?
他说他们一帮人刚刚越狱
He said his crew just escaped from prison,
如果不是为了拯救山达尔没理由冒险
so he'd have no other reason to risk coming to Xandar to help.
他说他确实是个
He says that he's an...
"混球"
"A-hole."
但不是一个
But he's not...
引用他原话就是
and I'm quoting him, here,
"彻头彻尾的混蛋"
"100% a dick."
你信他吗
Do you believe him?
我也不知道有没有彻头彻尾的混蛋  夫人
I don't know that I believe anyone is 100% a dick, ma'am.
我是问  你相信他是来帮忙的吗
I mean, do you believe that he is here to help?
信啊
Yeah.
不明舰队逼近中
A fleet approaches.
看起来像是掠夺者
They appear to be Ravagers.
开火
Fire!
掩护就位
Cover it down.
全体下潜
Submerge!
火箭  快上
Rocket, hurry!
全体飞行员下潜
All pilots, dive!
他们在我们正下方
They're beneath us!
疏散全体市民
Evacuate the city.
我们的首要任务是确保人民安全撤离
Our priority is to get our people away from the battle.
全速推进  动作快
Forward thrust, now!
加把劲儿
Come on!
奎尔  勇度  趁现在
Quill! Yondu! Now!
妈的
Aw, hell!
我被击落了  奎尔
I'm going down, Quill!
别给我耍花招  小子
No more games with me, boy!
完事之后我们再会
I'll see you at the end of this!
他们人太多了  火箭
There are too many of them, Rocket!
我们没法突围
We'll never make it up there!
彼得·奎尔
Peter Quill.
我是新星军团的丹纳利安·萨尔
This is Denarian Saal of the Nova Corps.
先声明一下  我始终认为不该相信你
For the record, I advised against trusting you here.
看来我的"混蛋"消息他们收到了
They got my "Dick" Message!
用事实证明我错了吧
Prove me wrong.
爽
Yes!
够嗨
我们和凯文·贝肯差不多厉害吧
We're just like Kevin Bacon.
右舷核心部位受创
The starboard kern has been breached!
他们闯进来了
We have been boarded.
继续向前推进
Continue our approach.
但是新星军团也掺合进来了
But the Nova Corps have engaged.
着陆之后一切就都不是问题了
None of that will matter once we reach the surface.
关闭所有安全门
Seal security doors!
赶紧
Now!
别挡老娘的路
Get out of my way!
老天
Oh, man.
所有新星飞行员听令
All Nova pilots,
全体对接形成封锁网
interlock and form a blockade.
务必阻止暗黑星号着陆
The Dark Aster must not reach the ground.
已锁入
Locked in!
Locked in.
已锁入
We're locked in.
我什么都看不见
I can barely see.
你什么时候学了这一招
When did you learn to do that?
我猜答案肯定是
Pretty sure the answer is
"我是格鲁特"
"I am Groot."
飞行甲板就在前方300米处
The flight deck is 300 meters this way.
我希望你们知道
I want you all to know that
感谢你们  不在意我的鲁莽之举
I am grateful for your acceptance
依然接受我
after my blunders.
再次有朋友相伴的感觉...
It is pleasing to once again have...
真棒
friends.
奎尔  你是我朋友
You, Quill, are my friend.
谢了
Thanks.
这颗蠢树也是我朋友
This dumb tree, he is my friend.
还有这个绿婊子也
And this green whore, she, too...
给我闭嘴
You must stop!
卡魔拉  看看你干的好事
Gamora, look at what you have done.
你还是一如既往的软弱
You have always been weak.
愚蠢  背信弃...
You stupid, traitorous...
不要这么跟我朋友说话
Nobody talks to my friends like that.
你们去飞行甲板
Head to the flight deck.
我去切断安全门的动力
I'll shut down the power to the security doors.
勇度·尤冬塔
Yondu Udonta.
命令自己的手下向新星军团投降
Order your men to turn on the Nova Corps.
玩够了没  掠夺者
Enough nonsense, Ravager!
你的死期到...
Time to die...
星云  别这样
Nebula, please.
够了  死灵舰队飞行员
Enough of this. Necrocraft pilots,
开始自我献祭吧
enact immolation initiative.
他们冲下去轰炸城市了
They're dive-bombing the city!
丹纳利安·萨尔  需要解除连锁吗
Denarian Saal, should we break formation?
不行  保持阵形
No! Hold your positions.
拖住罗南  萨尔
Keep Ronan up there, Saal.
下面市民的安全交给我们了
We'll take care of the people down here.
我居然要听命于一只小仓鼠
I can't believe I'm taking orders from a hamster.
星爵
Star-Lord.
终于记住了
Finally.
你个卑鄙的贼
You thief!
你们休想攻到罗南那儿去
You will never make it to Ronan.
在死灵舰着陆之前就把他们轰下来
Everybody shoot them before they hit the ground.
来吧
Come on!
手指划过喉咙就是杀人
Finger to the throat means death.
我用比喻了
Metaphor.
差不多吧
Yeah, sorta.
不是吧
Oh, no.
山达尔
Xandar!
接受制裁吧
You stand accused.
可悲的和平条约也救不了你们了
Your wretched peace treaty will not save you now.
跟条约一起葬身火海吧
It is the tinder on which you burn.
火箭
Rocket!
坚持住  萨尔  再坚...
Hold on, Saal, just...
奎尔  你得快点了
Quill, you gotta hurry.
市民倒是都被疏散了
The city's been evacuated,
可我们还在苦战呢
but we're getting our asses kicked down here.
卡魔拉还没把门打开
Gamora hasn't opened the door!
星云
Nebula!
妹妹  帮我们一起打败罗南吧
Sister, help us fight Ronan.
你很清楚他就是个疯子
You know he's crazy.
你们俩都是疯子
I know you're both crazy.
不
No!
什么鬼...
What the...?
滚出去
Get out!
你成功了
You did it!
之前我错了
I was mistaken.
我确实记得你家人
I do remember your family.
她们临死时的叫声
Their screams were
那么可悲  我
pitiful. I...
不  格鲁特
No, Groot!
别这样
You can't.
你会死的
You'll die.
为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
为什么
Why?
我们
We...
是
are...
格鲁特
Groot.
真是个白痴
I called him an idiot.
是你杀了格鲁特
You killed Groot!
看吧
Behold!
看这支银河护卫队
Your guardians of the galaxy.
你们护卫了什么
What fruit have they wrought?
现在我终于得偿所愿
Only that my father and his father
为我父亲和爷爷报了仇
shall finally know vengeance.
山达尔的子民
People of Xandar,
背弃你们卑微的信仰
the time has come to rejoice
迎接我的时刻到了
and renounce your paltry gods!
你们即将得到救赎
Your salvation is at hand.
听这几句
Listen to these words.
用力舞起来
Now bring it down hard!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
比舞啊  老兄  就我们俩
Dance-off, Bro. Me and you.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
委婉拒绝  收回邀请
Subtle. Take it back.
你到底在搞什么鬼
What are you doing?
分你的心啊  大蠢蛋
I'm distracting you, you big turd blossom.
不
No!
彼得  握住我的手
Peter! Take my hand!
握住我的手  彼得
Take my hand, Peter.
妈妈
Mom.
握住我的手
Take my hand!
你们只是凡人
You're mortal!
怎么可能
How?
你不是说过吗  婊子
You said it yourself, bitch.
我们可是银河护卫队
We're the Guardians of the Galaxy.
不错  不错
Well, well, well.
好一场光影盛宴
Quite the light show.
大团圆结局啊
Ain't this sweet.
不过在你们嘿咻嘿咻之前
But you got some business to attend to
先给我把正事办了
before all the nookie-nookie starts.
彼得  你不能给他
Peter, you can't. Peter.
你得三思  勇度
You gotta reconsider this, Yondu.
我不知道你要把它卖给谁
I don't know who you're selling this to,
不过能让宇宙安定平稳的唯一方法
but the only way the universe can survive
就是把它交给新星军团保管
is if you give it to the Nova Corps.
都说我长得像菩萨
I may be as pretty as an angel,
可我没有菩萨心肠
but I sure as hell ain't one.
快交给我吧  孩子
Hand it over, son.
勇度
Yondu.
决不能打开宇宙灵球  你知道的吧
Do not open that Orb. You know that, right?
你也看见它的威力了
You've seen what it does to people.
奎尔这小子还挺懂事
Yeah, Quill turned out okay.
当初没有按他爹的要求把他送过去
It's probably good we didn't deliver him to his dad
也许是个正确的决定
like we was hired to do.
是啊  他爹就是个混球
Yeah, that guy was a jackass.
等他发现宇宙灵球被我掉包了
He is gonna be so pissed when he realizes
非气炸不可
I switched out the Orb on him.
他一定会砍死你  彼得
He was gonna kill you, Peter.
是啊
Oh, I know.
不过他也算是我唯一的亲人了
But he was about the only family I had.
不
No.
不止是他
He wasn't.
你们怎么连这个都知道
Why would you even know this?
当初抓你回来后
When we arrested you,
我们发现你的神经系统有些异常
we noticed an anomaly in your nervous system,
于是帮你做了检查
so we had it checked out.
所以我不是地星人
I'm not Terran?
有一半血统来自地星
You are half Terran.
你母亲是地球人  至于你父亲
Your mother was of Earth. Your father, well,
他是某种我们从未接触过的远古生灵
he's something very ancient we've never seen here before.
怪不得
That could be why
你握着宝石那么久却没事
you were able to hold the Stone for as long as you did.
你的朋友们来齐了
Your friends have arrived.
我谨代表新星军团
On behalf of the Nova Corps,
向你们致以最真诚的谢意
we'd like to express our profound gratitude
谢谢你们拯救了山达尔
for your help in saving Xandar.
你们可以跟随丹纳利安·戴
If you will follow Denarian Dey,
他有东西要带你们看
he has something to show you.
谢谢了  新星至尊
Thank you, Nova Prime.
你帮妻女报了仇
Your wife and child shall rest well
现在她们能安息了
knowing that you have avenged them.
是啊
Yes.
不过说到底罗南只是个傀儡
Of course, Ronan was only a puppet.
得杀掉灭霸才算报仇
It's really Thanos I need to kill.
我们想保留它原本的样子
We tried to keep it as close to the original as possible.
已经尽全力做了相关修复了
We salvaged as much as we could.
我
I...
多谢了
Thank you.
我也有妻儿
I have a family.
多亏你她们才能活下来
They're alive because of you.
你们的犯罪记录已经被抹掉了
Your criminal records have also been expunged.
不过还是得提醒你们
However, I have to warn
遵纪守法才是好公民
you against breaking any laws in the future.
问一下
Question.
如果我拿了一件很想要的
What if I see something that I want to take,
刚好又属于别人的东西呢
and it belongs to someone else?
你会被逮捕
You will be arrested.
可如果我比物主更想要那东西呢
But what if I want it more than the person who has it?
-还是违法的  -说不通啊
- It's still illegal. - That doesn't follow.
我更想要啊  长官  你懂吗
No, I want it more, sir. Do you understand?
笑什么
What are you laughing at?
干嘛拉我走  我不能和这位先生聊聊吗
Why? I can't have a discussion with this gentleman?
如果谁把我惹毛了
What if someone does something irksome
然后我决定要抽了他的脊椎呢
and I decide to remove his spine?
那个
That's...
那个应该算谋杀了
That's actually murder.
最恶劣的犯罪之一
It's one of the worst crimes of all.
所以  也是违法的
So... also illegal.
他们会老实待着的  戴
They'll be fine, Dey.
我会看好他们的
I'm gonna keep an eye on 'em.
你
You?
对啊  我
Yeah. Me.
彼得
Peter,
我知道最近几个月对你来说很痛苦
I know these last few months have been hard for you.
其实我只是要去个更好的地方
But I'm going to a better place.
我会照顾好自己的
And I will be okay.
我会永远陪在你身边
And I will always be with you.
你是我生命的曙光
You are the light of my life.
我挚爱的儿子
My precious son.
我的小星爵
My little Star-Lord.
永远爱你的妈妈
Love, Mom.
劲歌金曲  第二辑
那么接下来做什么呢
So, what should we do next?
干点好事
Something good?
干点坏事
Something bad?
还是都干一点
A bit of both?
你说了算  星爵
We'll follow your lead, Star-Lord.
那就都干一点
Bit of both.
银河护卫队
.
即将归来
结尾还有画面
没有任何浣熊与树状生物在拍摄过程中受到伤害
你就随它那么舔吗
What do you let it lick you like that for?
霍华德鸭  漫威漫画角色
恶心
Gross.
霍华德鸭  漫威漫画角色
好爽
Yeah!
就是有点火辣
But it burns going down.